MATIJA JAMBRESIC

Bachelor of Computer Science, Software Engineering

Senior Gameplay and Network programmer

Linkedin in/mjambresic

Web mjambresic.com

Github

Email matija.jambresic@yahoo.com

github.com/mjambresic

Summary

Game developer with expert skills in C# programming. Specialized in making Unity games with more than 7 years of game making and programming experience. I am also familiar with Unreal Engine and C++, and hold a Professional Bachelor's degree in Computer Science, Software Engineering.

Skills

Expert Unity, C#
Gameplay Programming
Data structures
Source control Git. Perforce

Proficient Unreal, C++
UI and Animation Programming
Design patterns
OOP Architecture

Game Networking Server-Client Architecture Game-related Math Debugging and Optimization

Relevant Experience

Kick League - Project Owner, Gameplay Programmer

June 2023 - Present

After years of gaining industry experience, I decided it was the right time to consolidate my skills and build a professional product from the ground up.

- Set-up whole game architecture, friendly for clean code and fast iteration time.
- Worked with Steamworks, programmed automated tools for build uploading.
- Designed, built and programmed the user interface from scratch.
- Set high optimization standard, the game is running with over 700 fps on a 5 years old PC.
- Built highly polished gameplay, designed to feel good both on PC and consoles.
- Programmed state machine that controls the whole game, modes and UI.
- Used Unity Game Services and implemented async code for online lobbies.
- Added player progress and leveling system to the game.

Binx Games - Senior Gameplay, Network Programmer

June 2020 - June 2023

Remote work for a Zagreb-based studio, contributing to a multiplayer live-service game for one of the leading PC and console gaming publishers.

- Architectured complex multiplayer backend and various networked features.
- Programmed Gameplay and UI in Unity Engine and C#, also Unreal Engine and C++.
- Learned about porting games to major platforms like Steam, Nintendo, Xbox and Playstation.
- Implemented complex algorithms for various game-related scenarios.
- Handled input management system for big budget multiplayer survival game.
- Build an online communication system and player chat.
- Worked with complex first and third person animators.
- Implemented interaction system that works with static items or other NPC-s.
- Led game settings and localization implementation for multiple games.

Worked on a game to rival Hearthstone, from the Zagreb office, focusing on gameplay, UI and client-side programming.

- Worked with Client and Server side programmers on the team to deliver finished network features.
- Guided freshly joined members to utilize the use of tech like Unity, Git and other tools.
- Added social features like friends list, invitation to game, accept, decline and similar.
- Cooperated with audio engineers to create FMOD to Unity import process, sound implementation.

Lionfred - Mobile Game Developer

October 2017 - October 2019

This brand encompasses several mobile game IPs that I own and created during my bachelor's degree. I designed and developed these mobile games from scratch.

- Worked with one of the largest casual mobile game publishers, Voodoo games.
- Designed and created more than 10 mobile game prototypes and gameplay mechanics.
- Learned about important metrics like CPI and user retention.
- Attended online meetings and training sessions to enhance the business performance of games.

C LAB - Software Engineer, High School Internship

2015 - 2016

Completed a programming internship over 2 weeks in 3rd grade and every Friday throughout the 4th grade, gaining my first experience in a professional programming environment.

- Learned about sensor programming from highly skilled professionals using C++ and C#.
- Was tasked to complete game related challenges when they realized I wanted to program games.

Education

Professional Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science, Software Engineering

2016 - 2019

Međimurje University of Applied Sciences in Čakovec

- STEM Scholarship recipient, awarded to students with the best education scores in Croatia.
- Learned how to design and develop mobile, web and desktop applications
- Enrolled game development classes and assisted other students in creating video games.
- Developed a video game as part of the final project.

Computer Science Technician, Software Engineer

2012 - 2016

Technical School Čakovec

- Started my software engineering journey over 12 years ago.
- Well known school with 130+ years long history and high admission score requirement.
- First time learned how to program in C++, C# and other object oriented programming languages.
- Also developed a video game as part of the final project.

Languages

Croatian - Native English - Fluent